Right. Now that we've um handled Now
that we've learned try and catch, it's
time to talk about how to handle
rejection. Well, at least promise
rejection. I'm still not good at
handling other rejection, but promise
rejection. We will talk about how to
handle promise rejection. So, in our
weight function that returns a promise,
um inside of that promise, um there's a
keyword reject. And so instead of having
it resolve, what I'm going to do is I'm
going to have it reject and say big
scary error. And that's the string it's
going to return when it rejects. Well,
the first way I'm going to show you how
to handle rejection with promises is
with async and await. So to do that, I'm
going to create an asynchronous
function. uh my function and um
oh async function would help if I use
the right keyword and then in here I'm
going to await
the weight and I'm going to wait 3000
seconds
and I'm going to try
to await and then I'm going to catch the
error that results if this doesn't work
and and I'm going to log it. console.log
the error. So let's comment out this
code. So what I'm doing is I'm saying
run an asynchronous function. This could
be any asynchronous function, but in
this case um I am waiting. I'm calling
the wait function with 3,000
milliseconds. So 3 seconds. And in 3
seconds, it's going to reject it.
Meaning something's going to go wrong.
And we're going to give back a big scary
error. If we save this
and we come over here
and we wait a bit, we reload the page.
One, two, three.
Interesting. Let me go double check my
code. Actually, make make sure I'm on
the right tab here. Um, I am on the
right tab. Oh, I told you I always
forget to do this. I never called my
function. So, we'll call our function.
And now if we wait one, two, three, big
scary error. We got our error. And where
are we logging it? We're logging it in
this catch statement. So what happens is
if you call resolve, it gets returned
out here and you can store it. So I
could say let my value equal
the result of that. And so if we
resolved it, it would have returned into
my value. When we reject it, our catch
here grabs a hold of it and lets us log
it. And that is what you can do with
rejected promises. So if you make a
request out to the internet and they
don't give you back what you want, your
request will fail. In other words, it
will reject it and then you can use try
and catch to say, "Oh, that error is not
available this I mean that data is not
available at this time." And you've
probably seen this on websites where it
has a loading bar for a while and then
it says, "Sorry, couldn't retrieve the
data." The way they're accomplishing it
is they're doing asynchronous requests
to get the data and then once if they
get an error, they're showing it on
screen. In this case, I'm just
console.logging it, but you could
totally show it on screen. Now that you
understand how to do it the async await
way, in the next video I'll show you how
to do it if you prefer to chain vends